Main Navigation
---------------

[

](https://www.terrastaffinggroup.com/)

            * Illinois
            * Texas
            * Colorado
            * Indiana
        * * Wisconsin
            * Tennessee
            * Arizona
            * Oregon
            * Washington

Privacy Policies
================

View Our Privacy Policies
-------------------------

### Privacy Policy

Last modified: May 16, 2023

Terra Staffing Group ( **“Terra Staffing”,** **“Company”** or **“We”**) respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it through our compliance with this policy.

This policy describes the types of information we may collect from job applicants and candidates; visitors to our websites, technologies, mobile applications, and online services; and representatives of our business partners, clients, and vendors and enables us to perform our services.  This policy applies to personal information that is collected, used, or disclosed through the websites, technologies, mobile applications, and online services provided by Company connection with any of our recruitment, sales, marketing, advertising, staffing or employment activities. For residents of California, [please visit the California Privacy Notice & Privacy Policy link](https://www.terrastaffinggroup.com/terra-staffing-privacy-policy-for-california-residents/) at the bottom of this Notice.

Please read this policy carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding your information and how we will treat it. If you do not agree with our policies and practices, your choice is not to use our Website. By accessing or using this Website, you agree to this privacy policy. This policy may change from time to time (see Changes to Our Privacy Policy). Your continued use of this Website after we make changes is deemed to be acceptance of those.

Information We Collect About You and How We Collect It
------------------------------------------------------

Company collects, stores, and uses personal data to provide our recruiting, employment, and staffing services. We collect personal data about individuals who use our websites, apply for employment or engagement with us, or placement by us and those who are representative of our clients (including prospective clients). Company does not knowingly direct its services or obtain, sell, or share information from children under age 16.

Most of this data is provided by you directly when you contact us, submit an application, attend an in-person recruiting event, through phone conversations, contact us about our services, or during your outsourcing or employment relationship.

We also collect data about individuals who are employed or engaged by our clients in connection with our provision of outsourcing and consulting services to those clients.  This is generally obtained through our interactions with clients, suppliers, and service providers.

When you interact with a Company website or application, we collect data related to how you interact with that service by, for example, our use of cookies placed on your device.

We have set out further details below on the types of personal data we collect, store, and use and the reasons we use your personal data. Examples of information we may collect includes, but is not limited to:

### **Contact information, including but not limited to:**

* Name and surname
* Maiden name (if applicable)
* Address
* E-mail address
* Telephone number

### **Personal, identification and demographic information**, including:

* Social Security Number
* Passport Information
* Drivers’ License Information
* National ID Number
* State ID Content and Information
* Citizen and Work Authorization Status
* Gender
* Marital status
* Veteran or military status
* Date of birth
* Information about your contacts, including family members, dependents, parents, and next of kin names, dates of birth, and/or contact information

### **Recruitment and Candidate Information**, including but not limited to:

* CV, resume, and application materials
    * Education history
    * Employment history
    * Professional qualifications
    * Relevant skills and certifications
    * Interview and assessment notes
    * Citizenship and work authorization information
    * Insurance information
    * Background check and drug testing information
    * Motor vehicle records for certain positions
* **Certain Sensitive Information**. Sensitive Information is data consisting of racial or ethnic origin, health, and disability information.
* **Analytics Information, Cookies and Similar Data.** Information including but not limited to your IP address, login information, browser, operating system and platform, Internet and cellular service provider, location, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and version, the type of cellular phone you use, unique device identifiers, Information including cookies, clear gifs, log file information, and other tracking technologies.
* **Geolocation Data.** Information that can be used to identify an electronic device’s physical location.
* **Communications**. Information including content of emails, text messages, letters, phone calls, surveys, and comments you send, place, or post to Company or our employees, agents, affiliates, or representatives.
* **Information Supplied by Others.** We may receive personal information about you from third parties. For example, we may receive information from publicly available career sites. Additionally, you may choose to provide us with information processed by a third-party website, such as a job search or social media website. We may receive information from parties providing background and drug screening, identity verification, and work authorization information. We use this information to determine which employment opportunities may be a good match for you based on your skills, experience, and/or feedback from our clients or other third parties.

### How We Use Your Information

We use information that we collect about you or that you provide to us, including any personal information:

* **To communicate with you.** We may use information to respond to your questions, to communicate about this policy or our terms, or to communicate with you regarding any other purpose described in this policy.
* **To perform our services.** We use information to send job listings or contact you about a placement opportunity, or to identify new candidates or clients.
* **For employment purposes.** We may use your information for recruitment and hiring, to staff open positions at our company or with clients, to provide payroll and administer benefits, for travel arrangements and performance management, for record-keeping, for safety purposes, to meet legal and compliance obligations, or for other internal purposes.
* **For marketing purposes.** We may use contact, demographic and site usage information to communicate about our services and to provide information about Company and its affiliates and subsidiaries. This may be by email, phone, or text. It may also be on social media platforms.
* **To improve our services.** We may use your information to make our website and services better, and to keep our records updated.
* **To protect our Company and constituents.** We may also use your information to identify fraud, secure our systems, or for other purposes as permitted by law, including to prosecute or defend legal claims.
* **For other any other purposes allowed by law.**

### Disclosure of Your Information

We may disclose or share personal information that we collect from you as provided described in this privacy policy:

* To our subsidiaries and affiliates.
* To contractors, service providers, and other third parties assisting in providing the Company services and managing our internal business operations, including but not limited to support for recruitment, interviewing, applicant tracking, resume/CV management, infrastructure management, platform management, application services, marketing, data analytics, skill assessments, and drug and background screening to manage requests and questions from you, personalize or enhance transactions, verify, process, store, enforce, investigate and/or collect actual or potential transactions, or assist or respond to our consultants including, but not limited to, auditors and lenders.
* Company clients so that candidates may perform work for them and/or be considered by them for employment opportunities.
* Government regulators, law enforcement authorities or alleged victims of identity theft (i) if we are required to do so by law or legal purpose, (ii) if we believe appropriate in response to a lawful disclosure request, and (iii) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss, or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual fraudulent or illegal activity.
* To third parties in the event of a merger, acquisition, reorganization, restructuring, assignment, sale of assets, or bankruptcy or insolvency.
* To third parties as necessary to exercise our rights or to assist third parties in defending their rights under applicable laws, including, without limitation, to assert, defend, and enforce our property rights and to respond to legal process.
* Analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimization of our website.
* To any third parties in which you explicitly direct or consent for us to provide information.
* To fulfill the purpose for which you provide it.

### Accessing and Correcting Your Information

At any time, you may obtain a summary of your personal information on record with Company. You may also request that we dispose of any or all personal information about you, except for personal information we need to complete transactions or to maintain proper records of previous transactions. You can help us maintain the accuracy of your information by notifying us of any change to your personal information.

You have the right to opt-out of Google’s use of cookies by visiting Google’s [Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads). Alternately, you may opt out of a third-part vendor’s use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out-page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/).

We will process your requests in exercise of relevant rights in compliance with applicable privacy and data protection laws and regulations in the jurisdiction in which you reside.

### Data Security

We have implemented measures designed to secure your personal information from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, alteration, and disclosure. All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers behind firewalls. Company takes care to secure your personal information. We regularly monitor industry standards for securing information and review our physical, technical, and organizational security practices to determine how best to prevent the loss, misuse, alteration, unauthorized access, destruction, or disclosure of your personal information. Any personal data sent to us, either in writing or e-mail, may be insecure in transit and we cannot guarantee its delivery. Passwords must be kept confidential and not disclosed to a third party.

### Changes to Our Privacy Policy

It is our policy to post any changes we make to our privacy policy on this page with a notice that the privacy policy has been updated on the Website home page. Company updates this Privacy Statement from time to time, so please review it frequently. If we make significant changes to our Privacy Statement, we may also notify you by other means prior to the changes taking effect, such as, prominently posting a notice of such changes on our websites, providing notice of the change through our online portals, or by directly contacting you.

**Contact Information.**

If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Statement, or how we handle your personal information, please contact us via email at: Privacy@TerraStaffingGroup.com. Company welcomes comments and suggestions concerning this Privacy Statement. We are committed to respecting your privacy and protecting your personal information.

**Your Acceptance of These Terms.**

By using Company’s website, you signify your agreement to this Privacy Statement. Company reserves the right to change this Privacy Statement at any time.  

### BIPA Privacy Policy

**Terra Staffing Group LLC – Illinois Biometric Information Privacy Act Policy**

Terra Staffing Group LLC (referred to as the “Company”) has established the following biometric information privacy policy:

**Biometric Data Defined**  
As used in this policy, biometric data includes “biometric identifiers” and “biometric information” as defined in the Illinois Biometric Information Privacy Act, 740 ILCS § 14/1, et seq. “Biometric identifier” means a retina or iris scan, fingerprint, voiceprint, or scan of hand or face geometry. Biometric identifiers do not include writing samples, written signatures, photographs, human biological samples used for valid scientific testing or screening, demographic data, tattoo descriptions, or physical descriptions such as height, weight, hair color, or eye color. Biometric identifiers do not include information captured from a patient in a health care setting or information collected, used, or stored for health care treatment, payment, or operations under the federal Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996. “Biometric information” means any information, regardless of how it is captured, converted, stored, or shared, based on an individual’s biometric identifier used to identify an individual. Biometric information does not include information derived from items or procedures excluded under the definition of biometric identifiers.

**Purpose for Collection of Biometric Data**  
The Company and the licensor of the Company’s time and attendance software collect, store, and use biometric data solely for employee identification, attendance records and fraud prevention.

**Disclosure and Authorization**  
To the extent that the Company and the licensor of the Company’s time and attendance software collect, capture, or otherwise obtain biometric data relating to an employee, the Company must first:

a. Inform the employee in writing that the Company and the licensor of the Company’s time and attendance software are collecting, capturing, or otherwise obtaining the employee’s biometric data, and that the Company is providing such biometric data to the licensor of the Company’s time and attendance software;

b. Inform the employee in writing of the specific purpose and length of time for which the employee’s biometric data is being collected, stored, and used; and

c. Receive a written release signed by the employee (or his, her, or their legally authorized representative) authorizing the Company and the licensor of the Company’s time and attendance software to collect, store, and use the employee’s biometric data for the specific purposes disclosed by the Company, and for the Company to provide such biometric data to the licensor of the Company’s time and attendance software.

The Company and the licensor of the Company’s time and attendance software will not sell, lease, trade, or otherwise profit from employees’ biometric data; provided, however, the licensor of the Company’s time and attendance software may be paid for products or services used by the Company that utilize such biometric data.

**Disclosure**  
The Company will not disclose or disseminate any biometric data to anyone other than its licensor of the Company’s time and attendance software providing products and services using biometric data  
without/unless:  
a. First obtaining written employee consent to such disclosure or dissemination;  
b. The disclosed data completes a financial transaction requested or authorized by the employee;  
c. Disclosure is required by state or federal law or municipal ordinance; or  
d. Disclosure is required pursuant to a valid warrant or subpoena issued by a court of competent jurisdiction.

**Retention Schedule**  
The Company shall retain employee biometric data only until, and shall request that the licensor of the Company’s time and attendance software permanently destroy such data when the initial purpose for collecting or obtaining such biometric data has been satisfied, such as the termination of the employee’s employment with the Company, or the employee moves to a role within the Company for which the biometric data is not used. The biometric information will be permanently destroyed no later than six (6) months following the date of separation from any assignment utilizing biometric information.

**Data Storage**  
The Company shall use a reasonable standard of care to store, transmit and protect from disclosure any paper or electronic biometric data collected. Such storage, transmission, and protection from disclosure shall be performed in a manner that is the same as or more protective than the manner in which the Company stores, transmits and protects from disclosure other confidential and sensitive information, including personal information that can be used to uniquely identify an individual or an individual’s account or property, such as genetic markers, genetic testing information, account numbers, PINs, driver’s license numbers and social security numbers.

The licensor of the Company’s time and attendance software utilizes Biometric time clock technology that does not store the actual biometric data, rather a mathematical representation of such. These Biometric time clocks have unique resolution, capture size, and algorithms which make all biometric data virtually incompatible with other biometric devices.

**Company Name: Terra Staffing Group LLC (the “Company”)**

The employee named below has been advised and understands that the Company and the licensor of the Company’s time and attendance software collect, retain, and use biometric data for the purpose of identifying employees and recording time entries when utilizing the Company’s biometric time clocks or time clock attachments. Biometric time clocks are computer-based systems that scan an employee’s finger for purposes of identification. The computer system extracts unique data points and creates a unique mathematical representation used to verify the employee’s identity, for example, when the employee arrives at or departs from the workplace.

The Illinois Biometric Information Privacy Act, 740 ILCS 14/1, et seq. (“BIPA”), regulates the collection, storage, use, and retention of “biometric identifiers” and “biometric information.” “Biometric identifier” means a retina or iris scan, fingerprint, voiceprint, or scan of hand or face geometry. “Biometric information” means any information, regardless of how it is captured, converted, stored, or shared, based on an individual’s biometric identifier used to identify an individual.

The undersigned employee acknowledges that he/she has received the attached Biometric Information Privacy Policy, and that he/she consents to the Company and the licensor of the Company’s time and attendance software’s collection, storage, and use of biometric data through a biometric time clock, including to the extent that it utilizes the employee’s biometric identifiers or biometric information as defined in BIPA, and consents to the Company providing such biometric data to the licensor of the Company’s time and attendance software.

Featured Success Story
----------------------

### My New Job Turned Into A Fulfilling Career

The right job can unlock something that you didn’t even know you were passionate about.  That’s what happened to Erika Hillman.  We’ll let her share her story.   Back in 2021, I was living in Florida where I worked at Disney World in a few different roles. I worked in a restaurant as a Hostess, I …

HR Hotspot
----------

Looking for practical guidance, real-world solutions and best practices for managing the human resources of your organization? You’ve come to the right place!

### Next Up:

#### Purpose-Driven Priorities: On Time & On Purpose

Join productivity expert Kristin Graham on HR HotSpot to learn how brain science can transform your productivity. Discover strategies to combat distractions, prioritize effectively, and achieve intentional productivity. …

[Read More from Purpose-Driven Priorities: On Time & On Purpose](https://www.terrastaffinggroup.com/resources/hr-hot-spot/purpose-driven-priorities-on-time-on-purpose/)

**Locations**

* Arizona
* Colorado
* Oregon
* Illinois
* Indiana
* Tennessee
* Texas
* Washington
* Wisconsin
